[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：ECMAScript 5，新零件。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: ECMAScript 5, The New Parts.
所以第五版的完整实现现在已经全部完成了
So complete implementations of the fifth edition are now in all
最好的Web浏览器，也在IE10中。
the best web browsers, and also in IE10.
所以，它几乎无处不在。
So, it's almost everywhere.
因此，再次回顾标准的历史，
So again, to review the history of the standards,
第三版于1999年12月批准。
the third edition was ratified in December 1999.
第四版的工作几乎是在那之前一年开始的。
Work on the fourth editions started almost a year before that.
第四版试图解决我认为的一些问题
The fourth edition was attempting to solve some problems that I think
都是不必要的。
were unnecessary.
最终，它变得如此庞大，如此复杂，以至于无法完成。
And eventually, it got so big and so complicated that it was not completable.
那个项目连续十年每年都下滑一次。
That project slipped a year per year for ten years.
所以它最终被遗弃了，取而代之的是，
So it was eventually abandoned and instead,
我们做了第五版，从工作标题ES3.1开始，
we did the fifth Edition which started with a working title ES3.1,
表明这将是一个不那么雄心勃勃的尝试，以增加善意
indicating that it was going to be a much less ambitious attempt at adding goodness
第三版增加了两种语言或描述了两种语言。
to the third edition and it adds two languages or describes two languages.
默认语言和严格语言。
The default language and the strict language.
在这两种语言中，我建议不要使用默认语言，而是使用严格的
And of the two, I recommend not using the default language, but using the strict
语言是独有的，我们稍后将讨论严格语言中的内容。
language exclusively and we'll talk later about what's in the strict language.
因此，ECMAScript 5项目的目标是制作更好的JavaScript。
So, that the goal of the ECMAScript 5 project was to make a better JavaScript.
有很多人希望我们不能做出更好的JavaScript，但是
There are a lot of people who wanted us to not make a better JavaScript, but
创造一种不同的语言，当然有很好的论据
to make a different language and there's certainly good arguments for
这样做，但我认为标准化不是尝试这样做的正确位置。
doing that, but I think standardization is not the correct place to try to do that.
所以我们没有尝试去做一件大事，而是尝试去做很多小事。
So instead of trying to do a big thing, we tried to do a lot of little things.
我们试图使标准更符合实际。
We tried to make the standard conform better to reality.
有些情况下标准说，
There are some cases where the standard said,
实现必须做到这一点，没有一个实现做到了这一点。
implementations must do this and none of the implementations did that.
所以我们说，好的，标准显然是错误的。
So we said, okay, well, the standards obviously wrong.
我们应该使标准符合人们实际做的事情。
We should make the standard conform to what people actually do.
我们应该努力使浏览器更好地相互兼容。
We should try to make the browsers conform better to each other.
在有些情况下，三个浏览器制造商会用一种方式来做事情，并且
There are cases where three browser makers would do things one way and
微软会用另一种方式做事情。
Microsoft would do things another way.
微软非常慷慨地同意做其他人都在做的事情，
Microsoft very generously agreed to do what everybody else was doing,
那是一件非常美好的事情。
that was a very nice thing.
在所有浏览器都不同意的情况下，
In cases where all of the browsers disagreed,
每个浏览器都做了不同的事情，
where every browser did something different,
我们将其作为修正标准深层内容的许可证。
we took that as license to fix something deep in the standard.
如果每个浏览器都做了一些不同的事情，我们假设网络并不在意。
That we assume that the web doesn't care, if every browser does something different.
在这种情况下，我们可以进去做更深层次的改变。
In that case, we can go in and do deeper changes.
作为所有这些工作的结果，互操作性得到了改进。
As a result of all of this work, interoperability is improved.
JavaScript已经非常擅长Write Once Run Everywhere。
JavaScript was already very good at write once run everywhere.
有了ES5，它会变得更好。
With ES5, it gets even better.
所以我们ES5的首要目标是不要破坏网络，这真的是
So our number one goal for ES5 was don't break the web and that's a really
目标很难保持，因为任何时候你改变了什么，就会有东西打破。
difficult goal to keep, because any time you change anything, something will break.
我们确实在ES5上打破了一些东西，但我们真的很努力不去做。
And we did break some stuff with ES5, but we tried really hard not to.
现在你可以像我一样争辩，外面有很多东西，
Now you could argue as I did, there is a lot of stuff out there,
应该打破，但我们试着不打破甚至那些东西。
which deserves to break, but we tried not to break even that stuff.
我们希望为语言的用户改进语言。
We wanted to improve the language for the users of the language.
大多数对JavaScript持批评态度的人都不使用这种语言和
Most of the critics of JavaScript are people who do not use the language and
即使我们照他们说的做，也不会使用它。
would not use it even if we did everything they told us to.
所以我们尽量不要听他们太多，并不总是成功。
So we tried not to listen to them too much, not always successfully.
我们试着听你的。
We tried instead to listen to you.
我们非常关注第三方安全或mashup。
We paid a lot of attention to third party security or mash ups.
我们希望您可以将其他人的代码添加到您的页面中，并且
We want to make it possible for you to add someone else's code to your page and
不要违反您的安全或客户的安全。
have it not violate your security or your customer's security.
我们决定不去保护愚蠢的人不受他们自己的伤害，
We decided not to try to protect stupid people from themselves,
因为那太难了。
because that is just too hard.
所以我们，事实上，增加了一些新的方法，让愚蠢的人可以做一些极其愚蠢的事情
So we, in fact, added new ways that stupid people can do outrageously stupid things
我们稍后会讲到这一点。
and we'll get to that little bit later.
我们决定没有新的语法，原因是
And we decided to have no new syntax and the reason for that is
在我们做这项工作的时候，IE6仍然是占主导地位的浏览器。
that at the time that we were doing this work, IE6 was still the dominant browser.
我们担心的是如果我们推出新版本的语言
And our concern was that if we launched a new version of the language and
如果IE6仍然占主导地位，
if IE6 is still dominant,
然后如果新语言的值依赖于语法并且它将失败，
then if the value of that new language depended on syntax and it's going to fail,
因为每一个新功能都意味着彻底的失败，而这对你一点帮助都没有。
because every new feature means total failure and that's not helping you at all.
因此，我们试图在不改变的情况下为语言增加尽可能多的价值
So, we tried to add as much value to the language as we could without changing
语言的语法。
the syntax of the language.
希望最终我们能解决IE问题
Hoping that eventually we would solve the IE problem and
那么该语言的后续版本将能够更自由地使用语法。
then later editions of the language would be able to be freer with syntax.